# Deniss Borisovs

Senior Web Developer focused on Front-end

#### **DETAILS**

#### **ADDRESS**

Copenhagen, Denmark

#### **EMAIL**

deniss.borisovs@gmail.com

#### DATE OF BIRTH

September 27th, 1989

#### **NATIONALITY**

Latvian

#### LINKS

Personal website

<u>GitHub</u>

LinkedIn

Stack Overflow

## **SKILLS**

React Native

React

JavaScript

TypeScript

HTML & CSS

#### **PROFILE**

I am an experienced IT professional interested in exploring and applying technology to solve modern day problems. Currently focusing on Front-end (mobile/web/cross-platform) and cloud-native application design and development, with love for Open source software and knowledge sharing. Over the time of my career I worked with R&D, greenfield and support projects.

Updated on: December 4th, 2021

I am used to being a part of a productive team, but am also able to effectively self-manage during independent projects.

Actively practicing the following technologies:

- React/React Native
- Node.js/Deno
- Java/Kotlin
- MySQL
- RethinkDB, MongoDB
- CSS (SASS, PostCSS, styled-components)

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### Frontend developer, Sampension

February 2019 - Present, Copenhagen

Cross-platform Front-end development of a customer service application with React Native + react-native-web. Development and design of a microfrontend based solution using React for a back-office system.

### Senior software developer, ARHS Digital

January 2016 - January 2019, Brussels

Front-end development (Web and Mobile) with focus on UI/UX components and framework level re-usability using Angular and React Native frameworks as part of a consultant team for a large telco company in Brussels.

#### Senior Software Developer Analyst, Accenture

December 2015 - January 2016, Riga

Node.js CI/CD & Cloud SQL Kotlin Java Android development LANGUAGES English Russian Latvian Danish French

Front-end development with focus on cloud architecture (AWS, Azure, OpenShift, CI/CD). Building UIs for R&D projects in Cloud Management tooling in collaboratin with teams distributed all over the world.

#### Senior Software Developer, Accenture

September 2013 - December 2015, Riga

Web development for a Liferay platform based portal, development of web services (REST/SOAP), Front-end components with AngularJS.

#### Associate Software Developer, Accenture

September 2012 - December 2013, Riga

Software system development according to specification, following the decisions of architects and senior developers using Java / ActionScript.

#### Freelance Web developer,

October 2010 - March 2012, Liepaja

Web development on the LAMP stack, web deisgn, UX design. Typically the projects were websites for small business and landing pages for new start-ups.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Computer systems, Engineering bachelor Riga Technical University

September 2011 - July 2013, Riga

# Computer systems, First level higher professional education

Riga Technical University

September 2008 - September 2011, Liepaja

#### HOBBIES

I enjoy cooking, working out, DJ'ing with my friend and playing video games. I am a bit of a foodie and never say no to a good beer or coffee. Sometimes I can be found coding on a side project with a cup of coffe when I am in a creative mood.